Fionn MacCumhaill, hero of Aillen and leader of the Fianna,
and my daughter, Grainné, formally announce their engagement.
エリンの英雄　フィオナ騎士団の騎士団長　フィン·マックールと
我が娘グラニアとの婚約は　めでたくあいなった
Everyone, I want you all to celebrate tonight.
皆の者　今宵は盛大に祝ってほしい
That man with the mole beneath his eye...
目の下の泣き黒子が印象的な　あのお方は何とおっしゃる
What is his name?
He is Diarmuid O'Dyna, a knight of the Fianna.
フィオナ騎士団の一人　ディルムッド·オディナです
Diarmuid...
ディルムッド
Traitor.
裏切り者め
You will pay for this, Diarmuid.
許さぬぞ　ディルムッド
Take me with you...
私を連れて
お逃げください
...and run!
喜べ　グラニア
Rejoice, Grainné.
Fionn has recognized our marriage!
フィンが俺たちのことを認めてくれたぞ
Do you really think I forgot about what happened with Grainné?
グラニアの恨み　忘れたと思うか
A dream?
夢
Utw
Presents
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
The dream I just had...
今　見ていたのは
That was the legend of Diarmuid.
ディルムッドの伝説
Were they my Servant's memories?
これはサーヴァントの記憶か
Where am I?
ここは
気がついたようね
It seems you're awake.
Sola-Ui...
ソラウ
What is this...?
これは一体
Why am I here?!
わ　私はなぜここにいる
You don't remember what happened at all?
何があったのか　まったく憶えてないの
I...
私は
I was shot.
撃たれた
I defended myself with Volumen Hydrargyrum, but...
確かに「月霊髄液」で防御したはずだが
私の体に何が
What happened to my body?
There are signs that every Magic Circuit in your body went out of control.
全身の魔術回路が暴走した形跡があるわ
It's a miracle you didn't die instantly.
即死しなかったのは奇跡ね
For now, all I've been able to do is regenerate your organs.
とりあえず　間に合ったのは臓器の再生まで
Your Magic Circuits have been completely destroyed.
貴方の魔術回路は壊滅よ
You'll never use magic again.
もう二度と魔術の行使はできない
私は　私は
I...
Don't cry, Kayneth.
泣かないで　ケイネス
It's too soon to give up.
諦めるのはまだ早いわ
We haven't lost yet.
私たちはまだ敗北したわけじゃない
Sola-Ui...
ソラウ
If the Grail really is an omnipotent wish-granting device, your complete recovery should be more than possible.
聖杯が万能の願望機だというのなら
貴方の体を完治させることも充分に可能なはずでしょう
You only need to win.
勝てばいいのよ
If you succeed and claim the Grail,
everything will return to how it was.
勝ち残って聖杯を手にすれば　何もかも元通りになるわ
So...
だから　ね　ケイネス
Okay, Kayneth?
Give me the Command Spells.
この令呪を私に譲って頂戴
I'll take over as Lancer's Master.
私がマスターとしてランサーを受け継ぐわ
In order to bring you the Grail.
貴方に聖杯をもたらすために
N-No!
だ　駄目だ
You don't trust me?
私を信じられないの
I, who will marry into the Archibald family?
アーチボルトに嫁ぐこの私が
No, but...
いや　だが
Sola-Ui.
ソラウ
Do you really think Lancer would
abandon me and swear fealty to you?
ランサーが
私でなく君に忠誠を誓うとでも思うか
I do.
ええ　彼だって聖杯の招きに応じた英霊ですもの
He is a Heroic Spirit who heeded the Grail's invitation.
聖杯を求める心は私たちと同じ
He seeks the Grail, just like us.
Even if he has to change Masters, he will accept it to reach his goal.
たとえマスターが交代することになっても
彼は目的のために受け入れるはずよ
Sola-Ui!
ソラウ　ランサーはそんな殊勝なヤツじゃない
Lancer isn't as admirable as you think!
どうしてそんなことを
Why do you say that?
When I asked him what he'd wish for, he
replied that he doesn't seek the Holy Grail.
何を願うかヤツに問うた時　ヤツはこう言った
「聖杯など求めはしない」と
A Servant with no desire for the Grail is categorically impossible.
聖杯を求めぬサーヴァントなど有り得ない
何か本心を包み隠している
He must be hiding something.
だが　胸の内に何を秘めておこうとも
But no matter what he's hiding, he must obey me as long as I bear these Command Spells.
この令呪がある限り　私に従わざるを得ない
ケイネス
Kayneth...
I won't give you the Command Spells.
令呪は　渡せない
Kayneth, you don't seem to understand.
ケイネス　わかってないのね
That we must win this, no matter what.
私たちはどうあっても勝ち抜かなきゃならないってことが
You know, Kayneth.
ねぇケイネス
An unskilled spiritual healer like myself cannot
hope to extract ingrained Command Spells by force.
私程度の霊媒治療術だと
根付いた令呪を強引に引き抜くまでは無理なのよ
I can take these without resistance if the bearer agrees with it.
本人の同意があって　初めて無抵抗にこれを摘出できる
If you won't give me your consent, then I guess I'll have to...
どうしても納得しないというのなら
この右腕を切り落とすしか他になくなるけど
...cut your right arm off.
Well?
どうするの
Irisviel.
アイリスフィール
Don't worry.
心配ないわ　魔術による治療は被術者の負担が大きいの
Magical healing places great stress on the patient.
I think it'll be a while until she wakes up.
意識を取り戻すにはまだ時間がかかると思う
Please watch over her for the time being.
暫く　彼女を見てて頂戴
You're reporting to Kiritsugu?
切嗣へ報告に
I'm sure he's worried, too.
彼も心配してるだろうから
Irisviel, I have a request.
アイリスフィール　お願いがあります
I'd like you to talk to Kiritsugu.
貴女から切嗣に進言してほしい
Tell him we must pursue Caster immediately.
直ちにキャスターの討伐に向かうべきだと
Saber...
セイバー
Leaving Caster at large will only
result in the deaths of more children.
このまま　キャスターを野放しにしておけば
犠牲になる子供たちが増えるだけです
Kiritsugu?
切嗣
How long until we can use Maiya again?
舞弥は何時から使える
She won't be able to move for another day or two.
彼女は　ここ一両日は動けないわ
I see.
そうか
You and Saber stay here.
アイリたちはここに待機していてくれ
I'm going to go after Kayneth.
僕はケイネスの追撃に出る
ちょっと待って　切嗣
Wait a minute, Kiritsugu!
Did Saber say that we should go after Caster first?
セイバーはキャスターを早急に討ち取るべきだとでも言ったかい
Looks like I'm right.
図星か
Are you mad at Saber for not stopping Lancer?
セイバーに腹を立ててるの
ランサーを阻止しなかったから
アイリ
Iri.
Saving a few, or even a few dozen, children isn't our goal.
今　ここで数人　数十人の子供を救うことが僕たちの目的じゃない
Saber probably never doubted that Lancer wouldn't kill me.
セイバーはランサーが僕を殺さないと信じて疑わなかっただろうが
But what if Lancer had betrayed her?
もしランサーが裏切っていればどうなっていた
The Grail War would've ended for us right then.
その時点で僕らの聖杯戦争は終わっていた
There's no need to tell her where I'm going.
彼女に僕の行く先を告げる必要はない
Lancer.
ランサー
Please show yourself.
出てきてください
Sola-Ui-sama, how fares Lord Kayneth?
ソラウ様　ケイネス殿の様態は
Not very well.
芳しくありません
I've performed the routine treatments, but...
一通りの処置は施したけれど
This isn't your fault.
貴方に咎はないわ
Kayneth brought it upon himself.
ケイネスの自業自得です
It just means the Grail War was too much for him.
彼にこの聖杯戦争は荷が勝ちすぎていたということでしょう
No, but...
いや　だが
He isn't worthy of being your Master, Diarmuid.
彼は　貴方のマスターには相応しくないわ　ディルムッド
Kayneth has abandoned the war,
entrusting me with his rights as your Master.
ケイネスは戦いを放棄し　マスターの権限を私に譲りました
I pledged my loyalty as a knight to Lord Kayneth.
私はケイネス殿に騎士として忠誠を誓った身です
Sola-Ui-sama, I cannot give you my consent.
ソラウ様　その申し出は　承諾できない
What?!
そんな
To begin with, aren't you a Servant who manifests physically using my mana?
もとより貴方は私の魔力によって現界しているサーヴァントでしょう
And now I have the Command Spells, too!
そして今は令呪までもが私の手にあるのよ
Before I am a Servant, I am a knight.
私はサーヴァントである以前に　一人の騎士なのです
I can only serve but one lord.
忠義を尽くす君主は　ただ一人しか有り得ない
Am I not worthy of being your Master?
私がマスターでは不足ですか
That's not the issue here-
それとこれとは話が違うと
Look at me when you speak!
私の目を見て話して
Lancer.
ランサー
Fight with me. Protect me!
私と戦って
私を護って
Support me.
私を支えて
Win the Holy Grail with me!
私と共に聖杯を獲って
I can't.
できません
If Lord Kayneth has abandoned this battle, then I shall seek the Grail no longer.
ケイネス殿が戦いを放棄するというのなら
私も聖杯など求めはしない
We need a miracle to heal him!
彼の体を癒すには奇跡の助けが必要だわ
Only the Grail can make that happen.
それが叶うのは聖杯だけでしょう
If you feel responsible for his current condition...
彼の負傷に責任を感じるなら
If you wish to restore Lord El-Melloi's glory to what it used to be...
ロード·エルメロイの威信を取り戻そうと思うなら
You must offer the Grail to your lord!
貴方は主に聖杯を捧げなければ
ソラウ様　あなたはケイネス殿の伴侶として
Sola-Ui-sama, you speak as Lord Kayneth's partner and seek the Grail only on his behalf, do you not?
ただケイネス殿のためだけに聖杯を求めると
そうおっしゃるのですね
Y-Yes...
そ　そう　無論です
Of course!
Will you swear that you have no other desire?
誓ってくださいますか  他意はないと
I swear.
誓います
As wife to Kayneth El-Melloi, I shall bring him the Grail.
私はケイネス·エルメロイの妻として
夫に聖杯を捧げます
The look in her eyes...
同じ目だ
It's the same one Grainné bore.
あの時のグラニアと
I harbor no hatred for anyone.
俺は誰も恨んでいない
However, fate was simply too cruel.
ただ運命の巡り合わせがあまりにも悪すぎただけのこと
All I seek from this life is the loyalty denied to me in my last.
俺が現世で望むのは
前世で叶わなかった忠節の道
I don't want that sad fate to repeat itself, yet...
もうあんな悲運を繰り返したくない
しかし
In my previous life, I threw myself into many battles.
前世において　私も数多の戦に身を通してきました
There were times when I had to turn a blind eye to lives lost.
止むを得ず　犠牲に目を瞑ることもありました
That's why I can understand Kiritsugu's reasoning in this matter.
だから　切嗣の考えも理解できなくありません
However, the Holy Grail War has clear rules.
しかし　聖杯戦争には明確なルールがある
It's supposed to be a proxy war over the Grail by
means of Servants to avoid unnecessary bloodshed.
聖杯を求めて無用な血が流れぬように取られた措置が
サーヴァントによる代理戦争のはず
Is that not the case, Irisviel?
違いますか　アイリスフィール
If Lancer's Master and Kiritsugu hadn't
fought in secret, we would've slain Caster.
ランサーのマスターと切嗣が隠れて戦いなどしなかったら
キャスターを討ち果たせていた
We wouldn't have to worry about
more innocent children being killed.
もう無辜の子供達が犠牲になる心配も消えていた
Lancer and I could have finished our duel in an honorable fashion.
ランサーとは正々堂々決着を付けられていた
切嗣は考え方を変える気がないのでしょう
Is there no chance of Kiritsugu changing his mind?
これだけは信じて　セーバー
Believe me when I say this, Saber.
切嗣と私の理想を実現させるためには
For Kiritsugu and me to make our ideal world a reality, you are absolutely essential.
あなたがどうしても必要よ
Man, that drink felt good!
いやあ 気持ちのいい飲みっ振りですなあ
おうおう 忝ない
Ooh, thank you.
もう お客さんがいらっしゃるなら もっと早く教えてくれなきゃ
You need to tell us earlier when you have guests over!
いやいや 奥さん お構いなく
No, no. Don't trouble yourself, ma'am.
気取らぬ家庭の味こそが極上のもてなしであります故
There is no better welcome than the simple flavors of home.
まあ  まあ お世辞がお上手だこと
My, you're such a flatterer!
We couldn't help but worry about how Waver was doing in school in England.
イギリスの学校で上手くやっていけたのか心配でならなかったのですが
あなたのような頼もしいお方と知己を得ていたのなら
But if he's made friends with a trustworthy man
like you, then we were worrying over nothing at all!
まったく取り越し苦労でしたなぁ
いやいや　私の方こそ世話になっとったのですよ
Nah, I'm the one who's in his debt.
Look, he even picked out and bought these fine pants for me.
ほれこの格好良ぃズボンも　彼が見立てて買ってくれたのです
So how long will you be in Japan, Alexei?
それでアレクセイさんは　いつまで日本に
Oh, I should have my work here wrapped up in a week or so.
ええ　まぁ　ちょっとした野暮用が片付くまで　一週間ですかな
If you'd like, why don't you stay here with us?
もし良かったら　我が家に滞在なさってはどうですか
I'm sure there's enough space for another futon in Waver's room.
ウェイバーの部屋なら　布団を敷けばあと一人は寝られるでしょう
Right, Waver?
なあ　ウェイバー
フトン
Futon?
おお　この国の寝具ですな
Oh, the bedding the people of this country sleep on?
It probably feels strange to sleep on the floor
instead of in a bed when you're not used to it yet.
ベッドではなく床に寝るというのは　慣れないうちは奇妙なものでしてね
That's what's best about visiting foreign lands.
それが異国の醍醐味というものでしょうな
Unknown surprises give me great joy.
未知なる驚きこそ我が歓喜
No matter the age, Asia always gives me much enjoyment!
いつの時代もアジアは余を楽しませてやまない
正しくおしゃる通りですな
You're absolutely right!
I told you... to take spirit form... when you come and go!
出入りの時は 霊体化しろって
言っておいただろうが
霊体化したらコレを持ち込むことができんだろうが
But I couldn't have brought this back in spirit form.
そのために晴れてズボンも手に入れたのだ
I even acquired pants for that purpose.
To begin with, boy...
そもそも命じたのは 坊主
Didn't you order me to do it?
貴様ではないか
Why must I, King of Conquerors, go
draw water from some country river?
なんで征服王たる余が
鄙びた川っぺりで水汲みなんぞせにゃならなかったのだ
Because it's way more productive than
eating rice crackers and watching videos.
煎餅噛ってビデオ観ているよりはよっぽど有意義だからだよ
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Fuyuki
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Harbor
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
New Town, East
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
Mion River
Seichou
Seichou, South
なんだ 錬金術の真似事か
What's this? Are you pretending to be an alchemist?
I'm not pretending.
真似事じゃなくて
This is alchemy, idiot.
錬金術そのものだ 馬鹿
一体それは何なのだ
What on Earth is that?
術式残留物
Spellcasting residue.
水の中にあった魔術の名残さ
Remnants of magic present in the water.
Seichou, South
Fuyuki Harbor
This means someone was using magic near the river.
Seichou, South
Fuyuki Harbor
かなり河口に近い位置で
Seichou, South
Fuyuki Harbor
誰かが魔術を執り行ってたってことだよ
Seichou, South
Fuyuki Harbor
If we follow the lead, it may give us a clue to the location.
これを辿っていけば
その場所を掴む手がかりになるかもしれない
坊主 あの川の水にそんなものが混じっていると最初から気付いていたのか
Boy, did you already realize something like that was in the water?
まさか
Of course not.
But this city happens to have a river flowing right through its center.
でもせっかく街のど真ん中に流水がある土地なんだ
So it's obvious to start by looking at the water.
先ずは水から調べるのが当然だろ
ライダー
Rider.
Was there anything between these two locations?
Yatsu Library
Yatsu
ここと ここの間に何かあったか
An irrigation channel or a drainage pipe, maybe?
排水溝とか 用水路の注ぎ口とか
おう 一際ばかでかいのが一つあったが
Oh! There was one of considerable size.
それだ
That's it.
そいつを遡っていった先に　たぶんキャスターの工房がある
Caster's atelier probably lies at the end of it.
坊主 もしかして 貴様
Boy, are you sure you aren't an incredibly talented Mage?
とんでもなく優秀な魔術師なんじゃないのか
こんなのは優秀な魔術師の手段じゃない
A talented Mage wouldn't do it this way.
It's probably the simplest of methods.
方法としては下の下だ
You're making fun of me, aren't you?
お前 僕を馬鹿にしてるだろ
Not in the least!
何を言うか 下策をもって上首尾に至ったなら
Using a simple method to accomplish something impressive
far outshines using a complex method to achieve the same thing.
上策から始めるよりも数段勝る偉業ではないか
As your Servant, I am proud as well.
余もサーヴァントとして鼻が高い
All right!
よーし 居所さえ掴めればこっちのもんだ
Once we grasp his location, he's all mine.
Hey, boy.
なあ 坊主 さっそく殴り込むとするか
Let's go raid them right now.
待てこら 敵はキャスターだっての
Wait a minute, we're going against Caster here.
判っておる
I know that.
判ってない
You don't!
His class enjoys the greatest advantage when it comes to territory defense.
こと陣地防衛において
最強のアドバンテージを誇ってるんだぞ
Harbor
Fuyuki
What kind of idiot would just go bursting in?
そこへいきなり攻め込む馬鹿がいるかよ
Harbor
Fuyuki
あのな 戦いにおいて陣というのは刻一刻と位置を変えていくもんだ
You know, territories can change by the second in battles.
位置を掴んだ敵は速やかに叩かねば
Fail to strike the enemy once you know their location,
and it'll be too late to even regret missing the chance.
取り逃がした後で後悔しても遅いのだ
お前 なんでまた今日はやる気なんだ
Why are you so eager today?
Isn't it obvious?
当然よ 我がマスターがようやっと功績らしい成果を見せたのだ
My Master has finally contributed something of worth.
ならば余もまた敵の首級を持ち帰って報いるのが
As a Servant, I must also do my duty and bring back the enemy's head.
サーヴァントとしての心意気というものだ
まあ そう初っ端から諦めてかかんでない
Come on, don't give up before we've even started.
Let's just go see what we find.
とりあえずブチ当たるだけ当たってみようではないか
Things might work out better than you think.
案外何とかなるかもしれんぞ
大当たりではないか
Bullseye!
なあ なんとかなったであろう
See? Things did work out!
Caster seems to be away, unfortunately.
キャスターめはあいにく不在のようだな
貯水槽か何かか ここ
Is this some kind of water tank?
Uh, boy...
あ  坊主
I think it's better if you don't see this.
こりゃ見ないでおいた方がいいと思うぞ
What are you talking about?
何言ってんだよ
キャスターがいないなら
If Caster isn't here, we should at least search for clues to his whereabouts.
せめて居場所の手掛かりぐらい探し出さなきゃ始まらないだろ
That may be true, but don't do it.
そうりゃそうかもしれが　止めとけ
This is too much for you to handle, boy.
坊主 こいつは貴様の手にゃ余る
Shut up.
うるさい
Didn't I warn you?
だから なあ
I told you not to look.
止めとけと言ったであろうが
うるさい
Shut up!
Damn it, you're always making fun of me.
畜生  馬鹿にしやがって
Damn it...
畜生
This isn't the time for pride, fool.
意地の張りどころが違うわ  馬鹿者
Nothing wrong with it.
いいんだよ それで
I'd punch anyone who could see this and not bat an eye.
こんなモノ見せられて眉一つ動かさぬ奴がいたら
余がブン殴っておるわい
What do you mean you'd punch them, idiot?!
何が ブン殴るだよ  馬鹿
Aren't you standing there looking just fine?
お前だって　今全然平気な顔して突っ立ってるじゃないか
That's because now isn't the time for emotion.
だっておい
今は気を張っててそれどころじゃないわい
For my Master is in mortal peril!
なんせ余のマスターが殺されかかってるんだからな
アサシン そんな  馬鹿な
Assassin?
But that's impossible!
Assassin's supposed to be dead.
だってアサシンは死んだはつじゃん
This is no time to be surprised, boy.
驚いている場合じゃないぞ 坊主
H-How?
ど  どうして
どうしてもへったくれもこのさい関係なかろうて
None of that crap matters now.
However, one thing is certain.
一つ 確かに言えることは
Everyone who believed in their demise has been deceived.
コイツらが死んだと思っていた連中は
残らず謀られたってことだわなあ
Did they... run away?
逃げた のか
Don't drop your guard.
油断するでない
Two have been killed, but there were another two.
二人死んでもまだなお二人
At this rate, who knows how many Assassins might show up?
この調子じゃ
一体何人のアサシンが出てくるやら知れたもんじゃない
ここは  奴ら好みの環境だ
This is their preferred terrain.
さっさと退散するに限る
We should withdraw quickly.
Should we really leave this place as it is?
ここは このまま放っておくのか
You might find something if you looked, but let it go.
調べりゃ何か判るかもしれんが
諦めろ
We'll just destroy everything that we can for now.
とりあえずブチ壊せるだけは壊していくさ
If nothing else, it will slow Caster down.
それはそれでキャスターの足を引っ張る戦果にはなる
With his hideout in ruins, Caster can no longer run or hide.
こうして根城をブッ潰されれば
キャスターは逃げも隠れもできん
He'll have to stumble out into the open.
後はふらふらと表に迷い出てくるしかあるまいて
It won't be long until we put an end to them.
彼奴らに引導を渡すのも
そう遠い話じゃないさ
Hey-
判ったから
I get it!
やめろ それ
Quit doing that!
Let's get out of here, boy.
引きあげるぞ 坊主
Don't worry about it, Kirei.
そう気にするな綺礼
確かにまだライダーの切り札が掴めていない段階で
Indeed, it was unfortunate that they learned of Assassin's
existence before we could discern the nature of Rider's trump card.
アサシンの存在が知られてしまったのは痛いが
But from this, we now know that Rider's Master is a third-rate Mage.
この度の一件でライダーのマスターが三流の魔術師であることがはっきりした
Had they not been discovered...
なればこそ 彼らに露見していなければ
Other options would have been available to you?
他にも使いようがあったというわけか
Yes.
はい
While it's true that your plans are important,
確かに策も大事だが
常に余裕を持って優雅たれ
you must remain in control and graceful at all times.
Elegance is required, even in battle.
戦いにも品格が求められるのだ
But I never thought he'd be this boring.
だがあそこまで退屈な男とは思わなんだ
Another chance to discern Rider's trump card will surely come.
ライダーの切り札を掴む好機は必ずや訪れる
Have the Assassins continue to monitor Rider, but ensure they take utmost care in doing so.
アサシンには細心の注意を払って
ライダーの監視を続けさせよ
了解しました 我が師よ
Understood, my teacher.
Episode 9
Lord and Vassal
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
You infused too much mana at once.
魔力を一度に注入しすぎたんだ
あたしにだって手伝えることはきっとあるわ
I'm sure there's something I can do to help!
まさか冬木に行ったなんて
I can't believe she went to Fuyuki...
これが間桐の魔術だよ
This is the magic of the Matou family.
今から俺らパーティ始めるとこなんだよね
We're just about to start a party.
こんなんじゃ何もできない
I can't accomplish anything at this rate!
Next Episode
Rin's Adventure